

ANNIKA CHAUHAN

Software Developer

London, UK | www.annikachauhan.com | github.com/AnnikaChauhan

PROFILE

Creative problem solver trained as a Software Developer with strong capabilities in JavaScript and React. An inquisitive and logical individual with a passion for learning new things and finding innovative ways to construct clean code. Previous experience working with Microsoft VBA and Excel spreadsheets. Graduate from the University of Birmingham achieving an Upper Second Class with Honours in Mathematical Economics and Statistics.

KEY SKILLS

- Software Development: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript ES6, Git/GitHub, Bash & NPM/Yarn, REST APIs, Authentication & Authorisation, Networking, Hosting & HTTP, Unit Testing (Jest & Enzyme), Travis CI & Object Oriented Programming
- · Front-end Libraries & Frameworks: SASS, Bootstrap, jQuery & React
- Back-end Development: Firebase (NoSQL Database)

EXPERIENCE

Jan - April 2020

Junior Software Developer | nology, Moorgate London

- Completed a 12 week self-funded intensive Software Development course taught by nology. All code skills and tools learnt are covered above in the key skills section.
- Worked as a group of 15 on a client project for five weeks. Tasked with managing the
 project agilely, working in week long sprints and pair programming tickets for
 maximum efficiency. Responsible (in pair) for Authentication and Spotify API set ups.
- Facilitated communications with the Product Owner for one sprint of the project.
 Responsible for managing PO expectations, asking and answering any questions,
 conducting daily scrums, overseeing the ticket allocation/code reviews and delivering
 a presentation of completed work at the end of sprint meeting with the PO.
- Produced various personal projects as personal challenges and to demonstrate skills, all available on GitHub and portfolio site, details above.
- Participated in a week of soft skills training, comprising of content such as: productivity, assertiveness & professionalism, amongst many other life skills.
 Additionally, conducted a solo 5 minute TED-style talk at the end of the week.

May 2019 – Jan 2020 Data Analyst | WARC, Holborn London

Responsible for solely producing over 1,500 data analysis articles for clients relating to advertising expenditure, consumption and media cost, to relaunch the WARC Data platform. Built automated spreadsheets where relevant data could be input and summary articles would be produced on mass to be released to warc.com/data.

In May 2019, WARC Data had published approximately 700 articles since the product first launched in the early 2000s. By January 2020 there were over 2,400 articles on the site.

- Required to accurately and quickly clean and transform data received from supplier for over 20 markets prior to data being input into the automated spreadsheets.
- Produced a spreadsheet "database" and used VBA code to automate the creation of over 100 personalised reminder emails sent each week to suppliers.

Sept 2017 – May 2019 Several Roles | GreenZone Cleaning & Support, Battersea London

March 2018 - May 2019: Finance & Payroll Assistant

Sept 2017 - March 2018: Finance Assistant

Details relating to daily responsibilities and other projects at GreenZone are available upon request. Listed below are some of the most significant projects I worked on.

Sales Tracking System

- Developed a new system to log the Sales pipeline, producing various reports to inform the team of their successes/improvements.
- Conducted presentations to Management on the progress of the tracker's development/features and demonstrated how it's use to the Sales Team.

Fleet Management Database

- · Created a database logging system of all 30 vehicle expenditure and usage.
- Required to submit monthly reports to the Directors, including detailed analysis.

Timesheet Automation

- · Created an automated messaging system via spreadsheet formula to inform the Payroll team when an employee was not working their typical monthly hours.
- · Presented system to Management and a gave a tutorial to the Payroll team.

EDUCATION

2014 - 2017

BSc Mathematical Economics & Statistics | University of Birmingham

Upper Second Class with Honours

Key modules: Advanced & Applied Econometrics Statistics

Mandarin (Level 3 & 4) Game Theory

Mathematical Modelling for Economists

Dissertation Topic: Crime, Economics & Happiness

Extra-Curricular: Treasurer of Indian Society (2015 – 2017)

Summer Business School in Beijing (2016)

2007 - 2014

A levels & GSCEs | St Helen's School, Northwood London

A levels: Mathematics (A*) Economics (A) Art & Design (A)

GCSEs: 3A*s 5As 3Bs (incl. Mandarin, Additional Maths & History)

OTHER SKILLS

- Microsoft: Advanced Excel, Visual Basic for Application (VBA) & Access
- · Accounting Software: Sage 50 Accounts & Sage 50 Payroll

HOBBIES & INTERESTS

- Head of Costume Design for a voluntary community Christmas pantomime production, which sold 1,500 tickets and was featured on BBC Radio London.
- · Painting & photography mainly abstracts. Previously sold two of my paintings.
- Reading & learning about new things from languages (maintaining Chinese and starting Russian) to human evolution to yoga and spirituality.
- Blogging my journey on the _nology course articles available on LinkedIn.